<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Queene. Where as the Quenes most excellent Maiestie by hir highnesse proclamation in Nouember last, did apoint and limit the reading of the lotterie within the citie of London this. x. of January  ...</title>
            <title>Proclamations. 1569-01-09</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1558-1603 : Elizabeth I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1569</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A73944</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8008.7</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S125350</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99900575</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99900575</idno>
            <idno type="VID">173528</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A73944)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 173528)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 2062:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Queene. Where as the Quenes most excellent Maiestie by hir highnesse proclamation in Nouember last, did apoint and limit the reading of the lotterie within the citie of London this. x. of January  ...</title>
                  <title>Proclamations. 1569-01-09</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1558-1603 : Elizabeth I)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>by Henrie Bynneman, dwelling in Knight Rider streate, at the signe of the Marmayde,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1569]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>A proclamation reducing the value of lottery prizes in proportion to the sum collected.</note>
                  <note>At foot of sheet: Cum gratia Regiæ Maiestatis.</note>
                  <note>Dated at end of text: Yeouen at hir highnesse honour of Hampton Courte the ninth day of January. 1568 and in the eleuenth yeare of hir Maiesties moste prosperous raigne.</note>
                  <note>Date given at end of text according to Lady Day dating.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Lotteries --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England --  Proclamations --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Elizabeth, 1558-1603 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:173528:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:173528:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
            <head>By the Queene.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Here as the Quenes moſt excellent Maieſtie by hir high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe</hi> Proclamation in Nouember laſt, did apoint and limit the reading of the Lotterie within hir Citie of London this .x. of Ianuary. And by the ſame did giue ſtraight charge and commaundement to all and ſingular hir officers, mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters and ſubiects hauing therin to do, to prepare them ſelues accordingly, as by the ſayd laſt proclamation may appeare. Hir maieſtie perceyueth, that of ſome myſtruſt or doubtefull interpretation of the proceedings in the ſayde Lotterie, the firſt intention (to haue the collection and aduentures to haue a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mounted to a certain maſſe &amp; ſumme of money, (wherwith a great numbre the Aduenturers might haue ben largely benefited, according to a Charte therof publiſhed in Auguſt. 1567.) is not nor can not be accompliſhed: Whervpon it is thought meete (without any further, expectation or delay) to proceede to the publiſhing of the ſayde Lotterie for ſo much as is alreadie Collected, and to cauſe euery Aduenturer to bee truely, indifferentely, and ratably aunſwered, accordyng to the maſſe Collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, without any indirecte dealyng towardes any perſon. And to the intent that euery perſon hauyng any intereſt herein, maye vnderſtande what in reaſon to expecte for hys Aduenture. It is to be vnder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtande to all Aduenturers in the ſame Lotterie, that the very certayne ſumme of Money Collected, and chargeable to the ſame, is a Twelfth parte of the whole maſſe firſt by the ſayde Charte appoynted, and no more, as by due Certificat and good accompte thereof (by hir highneſſe Commiſſioners and Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers, being perſons of ſpeciall credite in that behalfe) made, hir Maieſtie is certainly enformed. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vpon all Aduenturers ſhall be duely aunſwered of their Priſes accordyngly after the ſayd rate: That is to ſay, To hym that ſhall winne the beſt and greateſt Lotte, the ſumme of Foure Hundred and Sixtene Pounds, Thirtene ſhillings and Foure pence, which is the iuſt Twelfth part of Fiue Thouſand pounds, before appointed to haue bene gyuen, if the whole Summe had bene Collected. And ſo conſequently eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry perſon to be aunſwered of the ſeuerall Priſes contained in the ſayd Charte, after the ſayde Rate.</p>
            <p>Gyuyng alſo to vnderſtande, that for the ſupplying of the full Numbre fyrſt appoynted by the Chart, euery perſon hauyng aduentured any one Lotte of the value of Tenne Shillings, ſhall be admitted to Twelue aduentures or hazardes, after which aduentures or hazardes, the ſaid rate of a Twelfth parte, ſhall be duely aunſwered and payed in readie money. And whoſoeuer hath aduentured more than one Lot, after the ſaid rate of Ten Shillings, ſhal be anſwered and payed in like ſort: which ſeueral aduentures, hazardes, or priſes growing of the ſaid Lotterie, ſhal be duely anſwered and payed (after the Rate of the ſayd Twelfth part) according to the appointment and promiſe contained in the ſayd firſt Charte.</p>
            <p>And for this purpoſe, all perſons hauing intereſt herein, ſhall and may begin to giue their attendaunce thys preſent Tenth day of Ianuarie, and ſo to continue.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Yeouen at hir highneſſe Honour of Hampton Courte <date>the ninth day of Ianuary. 1568 and in the Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uenth yeare of hir Maieſties moſte proſperous Raigne.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
God ſaue the Queene.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprinted at London by Henrie Bynneman, dwelling in Knight Rider ſtreate, at the ſigne of the Marmayde.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="license">
            <p>Cum gratia Regiae Maiestatis.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:173528:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
